[](javascript:void(0) "search")

Search for: 

            * Educator Growth & Development
            * Student Services
            * Educator Resources
        * Special Education Programs
        * Early Intervention
        * Specialized Programs
        * Health Services
        * Preschool & Child Care
        * School Readiness & Family Support
        * Child Care Provider Resources
        * * Business & Financial Mgmt
            * Procurement Services
        * * Information Technology
    * Human Resources & Insurance
    * Programs for Teachers & Administration
        * Educator Certification
    * Programs for Professionals
        * Specialized Student Services
        * Early Care & Education
    * Classes (_pd_ Enroller)
        * Clock Hours
    * Agency News
    * District News
        * Search News
        * * Search for: 
                
    * Events
        * Special Events

Search for: 

Privacy Policy
==============

Privacy Policy[Laura Martin](https://www.esd112.org/news/author/laura-martinesd112-org/ "Posts by Laura Martin")2024-03-01T07:54:19-08:00

_Effective date: January 17, 2018_

Educational Service District 112 (“us”, “we”, or “our”) operates the https://www.esd112.org website (the “website”).

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our website and the choices you have associated with that data.

We use your data to provide and improve our website and services. By using the website, you consent to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.

Information Collection and Use
------------------------------

We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide information and improve our website and services.

### Types of Data Collected

#### **Personal Data**

While using our website, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Data”). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:

* Email address
* First name and last name
* Phone number
* Usage Data

#### **Usage Data**

We may also collect information on how the website is accessed and used (“Usage Data”). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our website that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

#### **Tracking & Cookies Data**

We do not use cookies on our website.

#### **Embedded content from other websites**

Pages and articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, content feeds, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

Use of Data
-----------

Educational Service District 112 uses the collected data for various purposes:

* To provide and maintain the website
* To notify you about recent news and upcoming events via our newsletters (you may opt out at any time)
* To provide customer care and support
* To provide analysis or valuable information so that we can improve the website
* To monitor the usage of the website
* To detect, prevent and address technical issues

### MailPoet Newsletter & Emails

If you have subscribed to our newsletter, there is a good chance you will receive emails from us. We will only send you emails which you have signed up to receive, or which pertain to the services we provided to you.

To send you emails, we use the name and email address you provide us. Our website also logs the IP address you used when you signed up for the service to prevent abuse of the system.

This website can send emails through the MailPoet sending service. This service allows us to track opens and clicks on our emails. We use this information to improve the content of our newsletters.

No identifiable information is otherwise tracked outside this website except for the email address.

### Contact Forms

We use various contact forms throughout the website to collect information so that we can contact the submitter and provide the necessary services. Information from the forms is captured in our database when someone submits a contact form as well as emailed to the service provider. We store this information indefinitely, but we do not use the information submitted through contact forms for marketing purposes.

Transfer of Data
----------------

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to the United States and process it there.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

Educational Service District 112 will take reasonable steps to treat your data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Disclosure of Data
------------------

All the information collected and stored on the website becomes a public record that may be subject to inspection and copying by members of the public unless an exemption applies.   Information received and stored is subject to the Washington Public Records Act, Chapter 42.56 RCW.

### Legal Requirements

Educational Service District 112 may disclose your Personal Data when we believe in the good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary:

* To comply with Chapter 42.56, RCW, other state and federal laws, law enforcement or court orders
* To protect the rights, property or safety of another person, including our own rights or property
* To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the website
* To protect the personal safety of users of the website or the public
* To protect against legal liability

Security of Data
----------------

The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

Service Providers
-----------------

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our website (“Service Providers”), to perform website-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our website is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Data to perform these tasks on our behalf.

### Analytics

We use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our website.

#### Google Analytics

Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our website. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)

Links to Other Sites
--------------------

Our website may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site in a new tab or window. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

Children’s Privacy
------------------

ESD 112 does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18, on or through the website. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we are notified that someone under the age of 18 has provided us Personal Data and the person whose personal data was provided, or their parent or guardian requests removal of the data, we will take reasonable steps to remove that information from our servers.

Changes to This Privacy Policy
------------------------------

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

We will let you know via email and/or a prominent notice on our website, prior to the change becoming effective and update the “effective date” at the top of this Privacy Policy.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

Disclaimer
----------

ESD 112 neither warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published or stored on the website, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products or services linked to or from the website. ESD 112 shall not be held liable for any losses by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. While ESD 112 exercises reasonable care to confirm the accuracy and reliability of data on the website, portions of the data may be incorrect, incomplete or not current. Any person that relies on data obtained from the website does so at their own risk.

Contact Us
----------

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us:

ESD 112  
Website Administrator  
2500 NE 65th Avenue  
Vancouver WA 98661  
Telephone number: (360) 750–7500  
Email: [hr.dept@esd112.org](mailto:hr.dept@esd112.org)

#### [112 Staff Resources](#3093ae5710c15c503)

#### [Quick Links](#21fd9f94134314e99)

#### [Stay Connected](#30226ae0414b2db0b)

#### SERVING CHILDREN, SCHOOLS AND THEIR COMMUNITIES FOR 50 YEARS

ESD 112 equalizes educational opportunities for learning communities through innovative partnerships, responsive leadership, and exceptional programs.

#### Contact ESD 112

2500 NE 65th Avenue  
Vancouver, WA 98661

Call: [(360) 750–7500](tel:360-750%E2%80%937500)  

#### Language

ESD 112 acknowledges and honors the traditional lands of the Cowlitz and Chinook Tribes, Lower Columbia Peoples, Shoalwater Bay Tribe and the Confederated Tribes and Bands of the Yakama Nation, on which our school districts reside in what is now Southwest Washington. We pay respect to the elders and caretakers that have stewarded these lands throughout generations and that are still here today.

© Copyright 2024 Educational Service District 112. All rights reserved.

#### 112 Staff Resources

#### Quick Links

#### Stay Connected
